46 chapter 47 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 47 Hard
Times My new master I shall never forget; he had black eyes and a hooked nose, his
mouth was as full of teeth as a bulldog's and his voice was as harsh as
the grinding of cartwheels over graveled stones. His name was Nicholas Skinner, and
I believe he was the man that poor Sidi Sam drove
for. I have heard men say that seeing is believing; but I should say that feeling
is believing; for as much as I had seen before, I never knew till now the utter
misery of a cab horse's life.
Skinner had a low set of cabs and a low
set of drivers; he was hard on the men, and the men were hard on the
horses. In this place we had no Sunday rest, and it was in the heat of
summer. Sometimes on a Sunday morning a party of fast men would hire the cab for
the day; four of them inside and another with a driver, and I had to take them 10
or 15 miles out into the country, and back again; never would any of them get
down to walk up a hill, let it be ever so
steep, or the day ever so hot— —unless, indeed, when the driver was afraid I
should not manage it, and sometimes I was so fevered and worn that I could hardly touch my
food. How I used to long for the nice brand mash with niter in it the Jerry
used to give us on Saturday nights in hot weather they used to cool us down
and make us so comfortable. Then we had two nights and a
whole day for unbroken rest, and on Monday morning we were as fresh as young
horses again; but here there was no rest, and my driver was just as hard as his
master. He had a cruel whip with something so sharp at the end that it
sometimes drew blood, and he would even whip me under the belly, and flip the
lash out at my head. Indignities like these took the
heart out of me terribly, but still I did my best and never hung back; for, as poor
Ginger said, it was no use; men are the strongest. My life was now so utterly
wretched that I wished I might, like Ginger, drop down dead at my work and be
out of my misery, and one day my wish very nearly came to
pass. I went on the stand at 8:00 in the
morning, and had done a good share of work, when we had to take a fair to the
railway. A long train was just expected in, so my driver pulled up at the back of
some of the outside cabs to take the chance of a return Fair It was a very
heavy train, and as all the cabs were soon engaged ARS was called for. There
was party of four; a noisy, blustering man with a lady, a little boy and a young
girl, and a great deal of luggage. The lady and the boy got into
the cab, and while the man ordered about the luggage the young girl came and
looked at me. “Papa,” she said I'm sure this poor horse cannot take us and all our
luggage so far, he is so very weak and
worn up. Do look at him.” “Oh! he's all right, miss,” said my driver, “he's strong
enough.” The porter, who was pulling about some heavy boxes, suggested to the
gentleman, as there was so much luggage, whether he would not take a second cab.
“Can your horse do it, or can't he?” said the blustering
man. “Oh! he can do it all right, sir; send up the boxes, porter; he could take more
than that;” and he helped to haul up a box so heavy that I could feel the springs
go down. “Papa, papa, do take a second C said the young girl in a beseeching tone. “I
sure we are wrong I'm sure it is very cruel.” “Nonsense, Grace, get in at once, and
don't make all this fuss; a pretty thing it would be if a man of business had to
examine every cab horse before he hired it— —the man knows his own business of
course; there, get in and hold your tongue!” My gentle friend had to obey, and
box after box was dragged up and lodged on top of the cab or settled by the side
of the driver. At last last all was ready, and with his usual jerk at the rain and
slash of the whip he drove me out of the station. The load was very heavy and I
had had neither food nor rest since morning; but I did my best, as I always
had done, in spite of cruelty and injustice. I got along fairly till we
came to Ludgate Hill; but there the heavy load of my own exhaustion were too much.
I was struggling to keep on goed by constant chucks of the rain and use of
the whip, when in a single moment— —I cannot tell how— —my feet slipped from
under me, and I fell heavily to the ground on my side; the suddenness and the
force with which I fell seemed to beat all the breath out of my
body. I lay perfectly still; indeed, I had no power to move, and I thought now I was
going to die. I heard a sort of confusion around me, loud, angry voices, and the getting
down of the luggage, but it was all like a dream. I thought I heard that sweet,
pitiful voice saying, “Oh! that poor horse!
it is all our fault someone came and loosened the throat strap of my Bridal and uned the
traces which kept the collar so tight upon me someone said, “He's dead, he'll never get up
again.” Then I could hear a policeman giving orders, but I did not even open my
eyes; I could only draw a gasping breath now and then. Some cold water was thrown over my
head, and some cordial was poured into my mouth, and something was covered over
me. I cannot tell how long I lay there, but I found my life coming back, and a
kind voiced man was patting me and encouraging me to rise. After some more cordial had been
given me, and after one or two attempts, I staggered to my feet, and was gently led
to some stables which were close by.
Here I was put into a well- littered stall, and some warm GRL was brought to
me, which I drank thankfully. In the evening I was sufficiently recovered to be led back to
Skinner's stables, where I think they did the best for me they
could. In the morning Skinner came with a farer to look at me. He examined me very
closely and said: “This is a case of overwork more than disease, and if you
could give him a runoff for 6 months he would be able to work again; but now
there is not anounce of strength left in him.” “Then he must just go to the dogs,”
said Skinner. “I have no meadows to nurse sick horses in— —he might get well or he
might not; that sort of thing doesn't suit my business; my plan is to work them
as long as they'll go, and then sell them for what they'll fetch, at the knackers or
elsewhere.” “If he was broken winded said the farer you had better have killed him
out of hand, but he is not; there is a saale of horses coming off in about 10
days; if you rest him and feed him up up
he may pick up, and you may get more than his skin is worth, at any
rate.” Upon this advice Skinner, rather unwillingly, I think, gave orders that I
should be well fed and cared for, and the stable man, happily for me, carried out
the orders with a much better will than his master had in giving
them 10 days of perfect rest, plenty of good oats, hay brand mashes, with boiled
linseed mixed in them, did more to get up my condition than anything else could
have done; those linseed mashes were delicious, and I began to think, after all,
it might be better to live than to go to the dogs. When the 12th day after the
accident came, I was taken to the sail a few miles out of London. I felt that any
change for my present place must be an improvement, so I held up my head, and
hoped for the best end of chapter 47